livspace.com 2019-12-20

# Redefining the modern home lifestyle - Livspace.com

##  Privacy Policy 

Livspace takes your privacy very seriously. This privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) is intended to inform you about the information that is collected from you when you visit website and applications owned and operated by Livspace (the “Platform”); how this information may be used and disclosed; and how your information is protected. 

Livspace.com and is a property of and is hosted and operated by Home Interior Designs E-Commerce Pvt. Ltd., a company incorporated under the Indian Companies Act, 1956 and having its registered office at 1, St. Marks Road, Bangalore -560001. 

###  Acceptance of terms 

PLEASE READ THE PRIVACY POLICY THOROUGHLY AND CAREFULLY. The terms and conditions set forth below through the Privacy Policy constitute a legally-binding agreement between Home Interior Designs E-Commerce Pvt. Ltd. ("Livspace"), and you. This policy contains provisions that define your limits, legal rights and obligations with respect to your use of and participation on the Platform, including the classified advertisements, forums, various email functions and Internet links, and all content and Livspace services available on the Platform. The Privacy Policy is applicable to all users of the Platform, including users who have access and/or register on the Platform, and users who are also contributors of content, information, private and public messages, advertisements, and other materials or services on the Platform. 

###  Information we collect 

####  Personal information 

“Personal information” is defined to include information that may be used to readily identify or contact you such as: name, address, PIN code, email address, phone number, order details, user records etc. that is otherwise not publicly available. 

When you sign up on the Platform we collect personal information from (i) users who are interested in availing our services, (ii) design partners who offer their design services to Livspace customers (“Design Partners”), and (iii) service partners offering their services (“Service Partners”). 

Personal information collected from Design Partners and Service Partners may be partially or completely accessible to users on of the Platform or those availing our services. Personal information from users availing our services is partially or completely available to relevant Design Partner(s), Service Partner(s) and employee(s) of Livspace on a need to know basis. 

All information disclosed by you shall be deemed to be disclosed willingly and without any coercion. No liability pertaining to the authenticity/ genuineness/ misrepresentation/ fraud/ negligence, etc. of the information disclosed shall lie on Livspace nor will Livspace in any way be responsible to verify any information obtained from you. 

####  Personal information from social networking sites 

You may log into our Platform through your Facebook or Google account. If you do so, you must enter the email address and password that you use for your account. We will ask that you grant us permission to access and collect your Facebook basic information (this includes your name, profile picture, gender, networks, user IDs, list of friends, date of birth, email address, and any other information you have set to public on your Facebook account). If you allow us to have access to this information, then we will have access to this information even if you have chosen not to make that information public. 

We store the information that we receive from Facebook with other information that we collect from you or receive about you. Facebook controls the information it collects from you. For information about how Facebook may use and disclose your information, including any information you make public, please consult Facebook's privacy policy. We have no control over how any third party site uses or discloses the personal information it collects about you. 

####  Calls and text messages 

Livspace enables users to call and chat with the Design Partners, Service Partners through the Platform. As otherwise described in this policy, your contact information may be accessible to a Design Partner or Service Partner for the sole purpose of providing services. In addition, regarding the calls or chats, we collect information including the date and time of the call/chat message(s), and the content of the calls and chat messages in order to improve our customer service and quality of services. Livspace may also use this information for resolving disputes between you and Design Partners or Service Partners or other users, or for safety and security purposes, and for analytics. 

####  Age 

We respect children's privacy. We do not knowingly or intentionally collect personal information from children under age 13. By accessing and/or registering on the Platform, you have represented and warranted that you are either 18 years of age or using the Platform with the supervision of a parent or guardian. If you are under the age of 13, please do not submit any personal information to us, and rely on a parent or guardian to assist you. 

####  Refer a friend 

Livspace offers the opportunity to any user to share details of anyone who they think may be interested in Livspace or our services. This information is recorded and used only to communicate with the referee using mediums including phone calls and email, based on the details provided to Livspace. We believe that it is within the purview of the referrer to seek authorization to share the personal information of the referee. When the information is shared with Livspace, it is deemed that the authorization has already been obtained by the referrer. 

####  Communications 

During your interaction with Livspace, you may also participate in polls, surveys and feedback and personal information including call logs during such interactions will be collected. Further, when you communicate with us (via email, phone, texts, through the Platform or otherwise), we may maintain a record of your communication. When you use the Platform to communicate with others, we may collect and maintain a copy of those communications, in accordance with applicable law. Such information obtained from a user is gathered and utilized to ensure a greater experience for users and partners. 

####  Payment, billing and financial information 

When you create an account with Livspace and start (i) availing services from us, our Design Partners and or Service Partners (ii) offer your services as a Design Partner or Service Partner, you may be required to disclose information such as bank details, PAN card, Aadhaar card, credit card details, etc. in order for us to process your request. 

Additionally, Livspace may also collect information related to the manner and mode of payments usually adopted by you on the Platform, including details of your bank account, credit card and debit card. The financial information collected may vary in accordance to your interaction with the Platform and our Partners. 

####  Device and location information 

We collect information from your devices (computers, mobile phones, tablets, etc.), including information about how you interact with our services and information that allows us to recognize and associate your activity across devices and services. This information includes device specific identifiers and information such as location, IP address, cookie information, mobile device and advertising identifiers, browser version, operating system type and version, mobile network information, device settings, and software data. We may recognize your devices to provide you with personalized experiences and advertising across the devices you use. In addition, the information may also include your location. 

####  Information from cookies and other tracking methods 

This Platform employs cookies, web beacons and other tracking technologies to speed your navigation of the Platform, recognize you and your access privileges, and track your Platform usage. These help us in Platform analytics to give you a better experience. The same may be used to evaluate the success of our advertising campaigns. This includes information, but is not limited to, tracking how frequently you visit our Platform and use our services, time spent on the Platform, pages visited, links clicked, etc. 

We may use third-party advertising companies to help us tailor site content to users or to serve ads on our behalf. These companies may employ cookies and web beacons to measure advertising effectiveness (such as which web pages are visited or what products are purchased and in what amount). Any information that these third parties collect via cookies and web beacons is not linked to any personal information collected by us. 

####  Information from other sources 

These may include: 

  * Feedback including surveys and ratings 
  * Livspace business partners through which you create or access your Livspace account, such as payment providers, social media services, or apps or websites who use Livspace's APIs or whose API Livspace uses 
  * Financial services providers 
  * Marketing service providers 

Livspace may combine the information collected from these sources with other information in its possession. 

By choosing to provide any and all of the aforesaid information to Us, you are giving Livspace permission to use and/or store such information consistent with this Privacy Policy. Further, Livspace shall be entitled to retain your Personal information for such duration as may be required for the purposes specified hereunder and shall be used us only in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

###  How do we use this information 

####  Internal use 

Livspace uses the information we collect to provide, personalize, maintain and improve our products and services, including processing your order and providing you with end-to-end interior design and execution services. Additionally, the information may be used to improve our Platform s content and layout, to improve our outreach and for our own marketing efforts (including marketing our services and products to you), and to determine general marketplace information about visitors to this Platform. The information may be used for product development, testing and improvement of existing services and products. This allows us to develop new product features and also facilitate financial solutions and insurance that our connected to Livspace services. 

####  Providing services and features 

Livspace uses the information we collect to provide, personalize, maintain and improve our products and services. This includes 

  * Matching you with a suitable Design and Service partner to offer our design and execution services. 
  * Facilitating in-account activities during your project such as in-website chat. 
  * Processing and placing orders for your project. 
  * Process or facilitate payment for your orders. 
  * Offer, obtain, provide or facilitate insurance or financing solutions in connection with our services 
  * Perform internal operations necessary to provide our services, including to troubleshoot software bugs and operational problems, to conduct data analysis, testing, and research, and to monitor and analyze usage and activity trends 

We confirm that the information that we collect from you may be used in aggregate form in various ways to optimize and improve Livspace’s services, understand usage trends, analyse behavioral patterns, determine the effectiveness and usefulness of services and/or communications shared with you. While such information may be based on information about you, it will not identify you personally. 

####  Customer support 

Livspace uses information collected about you (including recordings of customer support calls after notice to you and with your consent) to assist you when you contact our customer support services, including to: 

  * Direct your questions to the appropriate customer support person 
  * Investigate and address your concerns 
  * Monitor and improve our customer support response 

####  Communications with You 

Livspace uses the information shared by you to communicate with you, including for the purpose of project updates, customer experience surveys, promotional offers and account information. The mode of communication includes emails, electronic newsletters, invitations, polls and surveys. 

####  Communications among users and with Livspace partners 

To offer our services, or to facilitate Livspace Partners to offer their services, personal information, partially or fully, is made available to users of Livspace. As an example, when you sign up to receive services from Livspace, your contact information including phone number and email is shared with a Design Partner and/or Service Partner to offer his/her service for your project. Sometimes, the users are allowed to contact each other for marketing purposes as well. 

###  How we share this information 

Livspace does not sell or transfer your Personal information (including your phone number, email address) to third-parties for the use of their own marketing. 

####  Third party ad networks 

Third party ad networks display advertisements on other websites based on your visits to the Platform as well as other websites. These ad networks, sponsors, advertisers and traffic measurement services, employ technologies such as cookies, JavaScript, web beacons, and others to capture information governed by their own specific privacy policy(ies). We participate in these networks to enable us and the third parties to display advertisement for products and services that might interest you. 

####  Analytics and reports 

The information collected is used to create analytic reports for both internal and external partners, including business partners and the public regarding the use of and trends within our services and ads. For the purpose of studying and sharing trends, we may share aggregated or pseudonymous information (including demographic information), that is limited to non-personally identifiable information, with partners, measurement analytics, apps, third party ad networks, or media. 

####  Public Posts 

You (including Design Partners and Service Partners) may provide your feedback, reviews, comments, content, other information etc. on the Platform (“Posts”). Your Posts shall have to comply with the conditions relating to Posts as mentioned in the Terms of Use. Livspace retains an unconditional right to remove and delete any Post or such part of the Post that, in the opinion of Livspace, does not comply with the conditions in the Terms of Use. [All Posts shall be publicly accessible and visible to all Users of the Platform.] Livspace reserves the right to use, reproduce and share Your Posts for any purpose. If you delete Your Posts from the Platform, copies of such Posts may remain viewable in archived pages, or such Posts may have been copied or stored by other users. 

####  Information disclosed at your request 

To avail Livspace service(s), you may give us consent to share such personal information, as may be required, with our Design Partners/ Service Partners offering those services. In the event of such a request, Livspace shares only the information necessary for them to offer the specific service. All Design Partners and Service Partners are required to follow appropriate confidentiality and safety measures to protect your data. 

####  New ownership or bankruptcy 

If the ownership or control of all or part of Livspace changes as a result of a merger, acquisition or sale of assets, we may transfer your information to the new owner, a third party entity (a "Successor") 

In addition, in the event of Livspace's bankruptcy, reorganization, receivership, or assignment for the benefit of creditors, or the application or laws or equitable principles affecting creditors' rights generally, Livspace may not be able to control how your information is transferred, used, or treated and reserves the right to transfer the information we have collected from the users of the Platform and/or services to non-affiliated third parties in such event. 

####  Legal investigations 

We may investigate and disclose information from or about you, as permitted by applicable law, if we believe that such investigation or disclosure is (a) necessary to comply with legal process and law enforcement instructions and orders, such as a search warrant, order, statute, judicial proceeding, or other legal process served on us; (b) helpful to prevent, investigate, or identify possible wrongdoing in connection with the Platform; or (c) helpful to protect our rights, reputation, property, or that of our users, subsidiaries, or the public. In such an event Livspace shall be under no obligation to inform you or seek your approval or consent. 

###  Data security 

####  Online and during your interactions with Livspace 

Livspace shall take reasonable steps to help protect your rights of privacy and your information (personal or otherwise) in an effort to prevent loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction of such information, in compliance with the applicable laws. This Platform uses physical, electronic, and administrative procedures to safeguard the confidentiality of your information. SSL encryption is used to protect your personal information online, and we also take several steps to protect your personal information in our facilities. Access to your personal information is restricted. Only employees and Partners (Design & Service) who need access to your personal information to perform a specific job or provide a service are granted access to your personal information. Finally, we rely on third-party service providers for the physical security of some of our computer hardware. We believe that their security procedures are adequate. For example, when you visit our Platform you access servers that are kept in a secure physical environment, behind a locked cage and an electronic firewall. Livspace assumes no liability or responsibility for disclosure of your information due to errors in transmission, unauthorized third party access, or other causes beyond its control. 

At times we may retain third parties to analyze data we collect on our Platform, and to administer the services provided (such as shipping, web hosting, etc. as described above), solely to help us provide and improve our products, services and Platform. These suppliers and other third parties are not authorized by us to use your personal information in any other way. We may have to use personal information to investigate complaints and protect Livspace and its members, in compliance with the law, your Membership Agreement and Livspace policies. 

While we use industry-standard precautions to safeguard your personal information, we cannot guarantee complete security. 100% complete security does not presently exist anywhere online or offline. 

In the unlikely event that we believe that the security of your personal information in our possession or control may have been compromised, we may seek to notify you of that development. If a notification is appropriate, we would endeavor to do so as promptly as possible under the circumstances, and, to the extent we have your email address, we may notify you by email. 

###  Links to external websites 

####  Information not controlled by Livspace 

This Platform may contain links to other websites or resources over which Livspace does not have any control. Such links do not constitute an endorsement by Livspace of those external websites. You acknowledge that Livspace is providing these links to you only as a convenience, and further agree that Livspace is not responsible for the content of such external websites. We are not responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide while visiting such external websites and such sites are not governed by this Policy. Your use of any external website is subject to the terms of use and privacy policy located on the linked to external website. 

###  Choice and transparency 

####  Accessing and Correcting Your Information 

You can update the details associated with your account by visiting My account and accessing the account settings on the Platform. You can also look up your payment information, details about your project(s), services, etc. You may also update the information yourself, if allowed on the Platform or request updation of your information by contacting Livspace at care@livspace.com

####  Marketing Opt-Outs 

We may send promotional or informational emails to you..You may opt out of receiving promotional emails from Livspace the opt-out instructions contained in the email. Please note that if you opt out, we may still send you non-promotional messages, such as meeting invites, project progress, etc. 

####  Cookie choices 

Most web browsers are set to accept cookies by default. If you prefer, you can usually choose to set your browser to remove or reject cookies. If you choose to remove or reject cookies, this could affect certain features of the Platform and/or services. 

####  Withdrawal of consent 

You may choose to withdraw your consent provided hereunder at any point in time. Such withdrawal of the consent must be sent in writing to privacy@livspace.com. In case you do not provide your consent or later withdraw your consent, we request you not to access the Platform and use the services and also reserve the right to not provide you any services on the Platform. In such a scenario, Livspace may delete your information (personal or otherwise) or de-identify it so that it is anonymous and not attributable to you. 

###  Amendments 

Livspace retains an unconditional right to modify or amend this Privacy Policy without any requirement to notify you of the same. You can determine when this Privacy Policy was last modified by referring to the “Last Updated” legend above. It shall be your responsibility to check this Privacy Policy periodically for changes. Your continued use of the Platform following the posting of changes to this Privacy Policy on the Platform, will constitute your consent and acceptance of those changes. 

###  Grievances and Disputes 

####  Grievances 

In the event You have any grievances relating to the Privacy Policy, please inform Livspace within 24 hours of occurrence of the instance from which the grievance has arisen, by writing an email to the Grievance Officer at privacy@livspace.com. 

####  Dispute resolution 

Any dispute, controversy or claim directly or indirectly caused by, arising out of or relating to this Privacy Policy will be governed by the laws of India and will be referred to confidential, mandatory and binding arbitration in Bengaluru, India. The arbitration will be conducted on an expedited basis before a single arbitrator appointed by Livspace in accordance with the provisions of the Indian Arbitration and Conciliation Act, 1996. The arbitrator's award shall be substantiated in writing and will be final and binding on you and Livspace. Subject to the above, you agree to submit yourself to the exclusive jurisdiction of the Courts in Bengaluru, India.
